Ahsan Kabir Rana



+01308686991



sheikhahsankabirrana@gmail.com



Afroza's Dream, Kha - 173/1, Middle-Badda, Badda, Dhaka



SKILLS

Front End Web Development

HTML, CSS, Boostrap, Taliwind-CSS, JavaScript, React.

Programming Language

C, C++, JavaScipt, Python

Others

Machine learning, Graphic Design, MS Office, Photoshop, Figma, Illustration, Adobe Xd

PORTFOLIO LINK

https://ahsansportfolio.github.io/webportfolio

SUMMARY

Problem-solving computer engineer. Seasoned and independent Front End Development in blending the art of design with skills of programming to deliver an immersive and engaging user experience through efficient website development, proactive feature optimization, and relentless debugging. Very passionate about aesthetics and responsive design.

EXPERIENCE

- Worked as a productive and positive team member to design, code, test, report, and debug operations.
- Managed front-end development in the company's Portfolio Analyst, Employee Track, and Account Management systems.
- Successfully identified, diagnosed, and fixed website problems, including broken links, typographical errors, and formatting issues.
- Helped to achieve a consistent look and visual theme across the website by promoting uniform fonts, formatting, images, and layout.
- Worked to assess competing websites in regards to content, look, and feel.
- Evaluated and became knowledgeable in new standards, technologies, and trends in website development.
- I did web development course from Programming hero.
- I had A+ in Web Based Software Implement Course.

EXTRA-CURRICULAM ACTIVITIES

- Senior Executive CUB Computer Society (2019-2022)
- O Public Relation Officer CUB Programming Club (2018-2019)
- Join Secretary CUB Cultural Club (2018- 2019)

AWARD & SCHOLARSHIP



SARAFAT CHOWDHURY MERIT SCHOLARSHIP [Three Times]



I got Leadership Award in March, 2022 for excellent performance for the CUB Computer Society and the Department of CSE.

EDUCATION

B.Sc in Computer Science and Engineering

Graduated with CGPA-3.72 from Canadian University of Bangladesh in 2022

HSC in Science

From Kobi Nazrul Government College in 2017

REFERENCE

Prof. Syed Akhter Hossain, Ph.D.

Head of Department, CSE & Dean, School of Science & Engineering Canadian University of Bangladesh Email: akhter.hossain@cub.edu.bd

Faria Tabassum

Lecturer
Canadian University of Bangladesh
Email: faria.tabassum@cub.edu.bd